all right I was gonna talk about a much
more controversial topic today so I was
spending like an hour trying to put
things together and so I've done very
little prep for this one but I think
it's just about telling my story as
opposed to global incentives incentives
matter for sure
but money is one incentive one way to
incentivize people in fact money is a
placeholder for the actual incentives of
like are you seeking power
are you seeking security are you seeking
freedom what is it that money brings you
I think one of the best questions to ask
for people leaving school or going into
university probably before you go to
university what are you gonna take
university is looking at what you would
do for free looking at what calls you
beyond money because that is its own or
in and of itself if the reward is in the
doing you don't need the monetary
incentives and so I should have paid
more notes cuz I was like my story have
incentive um the reason I'm doing this
video is somebody commented yesterday
aren't one of my videos about this this
rhetoric that gets said a lot which is
like well what if like what is the poor
have as an incentive if we just like
give the money so my story it is I am
poor and I am on disability which is why
I'm poor and my incentive to create a
better world doesn't come to make money
on it in fact I am disincentivize my
money I'm like my needs are covered but
and I have very limited energy and I
still want to spend some of that doing
this work for the greater good both
because I'm gonna benefit from it and
because it's what I'm capable of and
it's what I will do for free it is what
calls to me it is what every cell of my
being is like do this it's fun the doing
even if nothing ever comes from it I'm
enjoying the process of it and so the
incentive is that the incentive is a
vision for a better world that I see is
actually possible and so my only choice
is to move towards bad because otherwise
I have to sit and make yeah
of just being in this society which is
not so so great for me the incentives so
I very much because in my own personal
life experienced it when you take away
the need to work the like okay so you
still have food on the table you still
have a roof over your head but you no
longer need to work it doesn't mean you
stop needing to contribute it doesn't
mean you stop needing to have a purpose
and in fact it said now a deeper purpose
because instead of looking I had the
ability to work full time and now
probably even part-time in somebody
else's employment where I have to follow
those rules where I have to like get up
at a certain time and not nap for two
hours in the afternoon and be reliable
and things that are understandably
needed by an employee
I can't accommodate that so I can't work
but I can contribute from where I am and
the incentive isn't to make money the
incentive is to create something I want
to create but if I have struggles
because of the same disability that
makes me poor I have struggles in how to
create it in the normal system but I can
foresee I can see all the ways that we
can we can help each other create so if
you're not a good communicator you can
find someone to communicate and if
you're not great at the financial piece
you can find that and the incentive for
all of those people is like you might
hate finances and spreadsheets so you
think you could only ever pay an
accountant to be an accountant people
who are accounting true people who are
accountants like people who would do it
without the money are better at it and
they love it so yeah you can find
accountants that will do accounting
because we all have different things
that draw us in so the incentive to look
to help each other find what our passion
is because the more I help other people
find their accounting passion I don't
have to do accounting before I help
people find their graphic artist I don't
have to do and I'm not doing any of
those things so I think it's very much
the 1% who's like and if the poor is
very much used against the middle class
look what could happen
right but when you take away I don't
know in the hall I could do a whole
video on poverty and incentives and the
ridiculousness of social programs that
do incentivize people to stay on it
because of the way it's created more so
than because and then poor people act in
their best interest in how economic says
you should act and we look at them badly
like well does it make sense to work for
free does it make sense to work for
negative money does it make sense no it
doesn't and would you so at the same
time we're like oh you're inside like we
are incentivizing people to stay on
benefits but taking those benefits away
is not helpful we have to incentivize
them to find a Colleen to find something
and then contribute to society well
they're getting benefits yeah especially
if they have health conditions I don't
know if I did this topic justice in his
five minutes but video 7 for today my
kids about to wake up any any moment and
I wanted to free time until tonight
[Music]